# **PRATEEK DEVARAJU**

# **SENIOR SALES CONSULTANT**

# CAREER OBJECTIVE

Experienced sales consultant with four years of experience in the technology industry seeking an opportunity to utilise my strong communication, persuasive, and relationship-building skills to lead and grow a sales team, increasing revenue and achieving targets. As an MBA student, I am eager to bring my passion for sales and desire for continuous learning and professional growth to a company in the sales industry and make a positive impact in a dynamic and growth-oriented environment.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Campus Ambassador

Aston University I Feb 2023 - Present / Birmingham, United Kingdom

- Successfully represented Aston University at various on-campus and off-campus events, including open days, student fairs, and recruitment drives, resulting in an increased number of prospective students and applicants.
- Conducted engaging campus tours and information sessions for over 100 prospective students and their families, answering their questions and providing an insight into the university's academic and social environment.
- Created and distributed promotional materials such as flyers and social media posts, resulting in a 25% increase in student attendance at university events.
- Collaborated with other Student/Campus Ambassadors and university staff to organize and execute a series of successful events aimed at promoting a sense of community and inclusivity, which received positive feedback from both students.

#### **Senior Sales Consultant**

Alien Technology Transfer Pvt Ltd / May 2020 - July 2022 / Hyderabad, India

- Secured 100 new SME's by utilizing cold calling and LinkedIn Sales Navigator techniques, resulting in a 123% increase in total customer acquisition within a vear.
- Nurtured relationships with 7 Venture Capitalists, presenting tailored services and qualifying startups for investment under their portfolio, which increased client sales to 60% over 2 years.
- Conducted market research by analysing their competitor analysis, financial statements, identifying their consumer segments, stakeholder analysis, and market constraints:
- Presented detailed feedback on the project analyses to C-level executives, driving successful negotiations and securing contractual & pricing terms for the onboarding process with 90% efficiency for the Innovate UK and European Innovation Council grant schemes.
- Devised business strategies to strengthen customer relations, achieving an 89% retaining rate over the expiration of existing agreements.

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**



+44 7383301478



pratheek.devraj@gmail.com



Street, Birmingham B6 4AS



n Prateek Devaraju Linkedin Profile



Prateek Devaraju Portfolio

## **EDUCATION**

**Master of Business** Administration

Specialisation in International Marketing Aston Business School, UK

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

**Bachelor of Engineering Computer Science** Aug 2013 - May 2018

#### **SKILLS**

**Industry Experience:** SaaS, IoT, Cloud solution and public and private fundings.

**Business Skills:** Leadership, sales and management skills, presentation skills, business writing skills, business

**Interpersonal Skills:** 

Consulting, communication, relationship management and analytical skills.

#### **Product Sales Consultant**

Magnum Networks Support Pvt Ltd / May 2020 - July 2022 / Bangalore, India

- Utilized consultative sales techniques to generate new business and increase revenue for Magnum Networks Support.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with clients by providing excellent customer service and support throughout the sales process.
- Conducted product demonstrations and presentations to showcase the benefits and features of Cisco, Juniper Networks, HP & Commscope's products and services.
- Surpassed sales targets by 15% through building relationships with cloud providers, presenting tailored cloud solutions and collaborating on product roadmap creation.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including the pre sales, project management, and accounts, to complete networking activities and meet project deadlines, ensuring the company's commitment to customer satisfaction.
- Worked with regional sales teams to develop strategy key points within the target accounts and managed the knowledge repository for the team as the central source of the submitted bids and company content.
- Significantly boosted revenue by effectively developing business with existing clients and successfully acquiring new customers.
- Constructed customized cloud solutions to meet Service Provider needs, securing an additional 35 enterprise accounts.

Clients: Quest Global, Standard Chartered Bank & Willis Tower Watson

Technical Skills: Microsoft Word, Microsoft 365, Salesforce, Microsoft, Azure Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Microsoft teams, SharePoint, SQL, Tableau, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

#### **AWARDS**

Aston Scholarship Award – Awarded an MBA Aston Enterprise Scholarship 20% in 2022.

Best Closer at Alien
Technology Transfer –
Received recognition and
incentive for being the best
performer in 2021 for Q1 and Q3
closing a total of 26 and 29

Magnum Networks Support: Won the Sales Excellence Award for achieving the highest number of new business acquisitions for the company in 2019.